A Guide to the Papers of Edythe C. Harrison 1961-1993
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library, Old Dominion University
- General Papers
  - Education
    - Drop Out Information (Box-folder Box 67, Folder 13)
    - Establishing VVEF (Box-folder Box 67, Folder 14)
    - Appropriation-VVEF (Box-folder Box 67, Folder 15)
    - Articles of Incorporation-VVEF (Box-folder Box 67, Folder 16)
    - Articulation Plan-VVEF (Box-folder Box 67, Folder 17)
    - Associated General Contractors (Box-folder Box 67, Folder 18)
    - Audit-VVEF (Box-folder Box 67, Folder 19)
    - Awards Program (Box-folder Box 67, Folder 20)
    - Boston Private Industry Council (Box-folder Box 67, Folder 21)
    - VVEF Materials (Box-folder Box 68, Folder 1)
    - Local Foundations (Box-folder Box 68, Folder 2)
    - FAXVO Facts (Box-folder Box 68, Folder 3)
    - Educational Material (Used for Speeches) (Box-folder Box 68, Folder 4)
    - Leglislation Studies (Box-folder Box 68, Folder 5)
    - Virginia Partnership of Education and Business 1993 (Box-folder Box 68, Folder 6)
  - Abortion and V.O.I.C.E. (Virginians Organized for Informed Community Expression)
    - Syracuse University-The Institute for Family Research and Education (Box-folder Box 68, Folder 7)
    - Abortion Debate-Newspaper Articles 1985 (Box-folder Box 68, Folder 8)
    - Abortion Legislation 1982 (Box-folder Box 68, Folder 9)
    - Constituent Correspondence, Anti-Abortion 1982 (Box-folder Box 68, Folder 10)
    - Medicaid Funding for Abortion (Box-folder Box 68, Folder 11)
    - Abortion-Parental Consent (Box-folder Box 68, Folder 12)
    - Harrison article-Parental Consent 1985 (Box-folder Box 68, Folder 13)
    - Abortion-The Silent Scream (Box-folder Box 68, Folder 14)
    - Abortion-Votes Parental Consent (Box-folder Box 68, Folder 15)
    - VOKAL Conference September 12, 1981 (Box-folder Box 68, Folder 16)
    - Abortion Reference Materials (Box-folder Box 68, Folder 17)
    - The Hyde Amendment (Box-folder Box 69, Folder 1)
    - Virginia Forum-Edythe Harrison articles on Parental Consent (Box-folder Box 69, Folder 2)
    - Parental Notification-HB 1915 1989 (Box-folder Box 69, Folder 3)
    - Virginia Pro-Choice Alliance 1985 (Box-folder Box 69, Folder 4)
    - Pro-Choice Current and Polling Data September 1992 (Box-folder Box 69, Folder 5)
    - Briefs-Democratic Women on Defense (Box-folder Box 69, Folder 6)
    - Newspaper (Box-folder Box 69, Folder 7)
    - Abortion, Miscellaneous (Box-folder Box 69, Folder 8)
    - Pro-Choice Alliance 1986-1987 (Box-folder Box 69, Folder 9)
    - Pro-Choice Alliance July-August 1989 (Box-folder Box 69, Folder 10)
    - Pro-Choice Alliance 1990-1991 (Box-folder Box 69, Folder 11)
    - Editorials (Box-folder Box 69, Folder 12)
    - Press Conference Reference Materials (Box-folder Box 69, Folder 13)
    - Letters to Elected Officals (Box-folder Box 69, Folder 14)
    - NARAL-News Articles (Box-folder Box 69, Folder 15)
    - Pro-Choice Alliance Positive Action Campaign 1990 (Box-folder Box 69, Folder 16)
    - Black Women (Box-folder Box 69, Folder 17)
    - Ad-hoc Meetings of Pro-Choice Oraganizations (Box-folder Box 69, Folder 18)
    - Newspaper Clippings (Box-folder Box 69, Folder 19)
    - Survey Research Poll Questions 1990 (Box-folder Box 69, Folder 20)
    - NARAL Parental Consent (Box-folder Box 69, Folder 21)
    - ACLU (Box-folder Box 69, Folder 22)
    - Planned Parenthood (Box-folder Box 69, Folder 23)
    - Virginia League for Planned Parenthood (Box-folder Box 69, Folder 24)
    - Connecticut's Abortion Law (Box-folder Box 69, Folder 25)
    - Maine's Bill (Box-folder Box 69, Folder 26)
    - Senator Granger MacFarlane (Box-folder Box 69, Folder 27)
    - Harrison Editorial with Glenn's Suggestion (Box-folder Box 69, Folder 28)
    - Norfolk Academy of Medicine Inc. Statement (Box-folder Box 69, Folder 29)
    - NOW Budget Pro-Choice Alliance (Box-folder Box 70, Folder 1)
    - Notepad with Miscellaneous Notes (Box-folder Box 70, Folder 2)
    - Pro-Choice Alliance Miscellaneous (Box-folder Box 70, Folder 3)
    - Articles re: Abortion July-August 1989 (Box-folder Box 70, Folder 4)
    - V.O.I.C.E.-Abortion: American Jewish Congress Statement (Box-folder Box 70, Folder 5)
    - V.O.I.C.E.-Mrs. Willian C. Battle (Box-folder Box 70, Folder 6)
    - V.O.I.C.E.-Teenage Birth Control (Box-folder Box 70, Folder 7)
    - V.O.I.C.E.-Board of Directors Meetings: Minutes 1981 (Box-folder Box 70, Folder 8)
    - V.O.I.C.E.-Budget 1982 (Box-folder Box 70, Folder 9)
    - V.O.I.C.E.-Correspondence 1980-1982 (Box-folder Box 70, Folder 10)
    - V.O.I.C.E.-IRS Exemption 1981 (Box-folder Box 70, Folder 11)
    - V.O.I.C.E.-Reported Use of Human Fetuses in Cosmetics (Box-folder Box 70, Folder 12)
    - V.O.I.C.E.-In-Vitro Clinic at EVMS (Box-folder Box 70, Folder 13)
    - V.O.I.C.E.-News Articles and Letters Medicaid Aborion Legislation General Assembely 1981 (Box-folder Box 70, Folder 14)
    - V.O.I.C.E.-Abortion Senate Bill #158 Helms-Hyde Bill (Box-folder Box 70, Folder 15)
    - V.O.I.C.E.-News Article Family Planning and Sex Education (Box-folder Box 70, Folder 16)
    - V.O.I.C.E.-Articles of Incorporation, Position Paper, Board of Diriectors (Box-folder Box 70, Folder 17)
    - V.O.I.C.E.-Meetings (Box-folder Box 70, Folder 18)
    - V.O.I.C.E.-News Articles Organizational References (Box-folder Box 70, Folder 19)
    - V.O.I.C.E.-Roe V. Wade (Box-folder Box 70, Folder 20)
    - V.O.I.C.E.-Abortion The Norfolk Academy of Medicine's Statement opposing S. 158 (Box-folder Box 70, Folder 21)
    - V.O.I.C.E.-Human Life Amendment Forum July 7, 1981 (Box-folder Box 70, Folder 22)
    - V.O.I.C.E.-Newsletters (Box-folder Box 70, Folder 23)
    - V.O.I.C.E.-Pro-Life Material (Box-folder Box 70, Folder 24)
    - V.O.I.C.E.-News Articles: Pro-Abortion Clippings (Box-folder Box 71, Folder 1)
    - V.O.I.C.E.-Human Life Amendment (Box-folder Box 71, Folder 2)
    - V.O.I.C.E.-Pro-Choice Editorial Drafts (Box-folder Box 71, Folder 3)
    - V.O.I.C.E.-Abortion Rebublican Platform (Box-folder Box 71, Folder 4)
    - V.O.I.C.E.-Rape Article from Delegate Joan Jones (Box-folder Box 71, Folder 5)
    - V.O.I.C.E.-Remarks for NBC News and Commentary Article March 9, 1981 (Box-folder Box 71, Folder 6)
    - V.O.I.C.E.-Abortion: Senator Warner (Box-folder Box 71, Folder 7)
    - V.O.I.C.E.-Teenage Pregnancy (Box-folder Box 71, Folder 8)
    - V.O.I.C.E.-Testimony, General Assembely from Abortion Hearings 1981 (Box-folder Box 71, Folder 9)
    - V.O.I.C.E.-Update on Senate Bill #158 (Box-folder Box 71, Folder 10)
    - V.O.I.C.E.-Abortion: Hatch-Ashbrook Amendment (Box-folder Box 71, Folder 11)
    - V.O.I.C.E.-Amniocentesis (Box-folder Box 71, Folder 12)
    - V.O.I.C.E.-Family Protection Act (Box-folder Box 71, Folder 13)
    - V.O.I.C.E.-Abortion: Physicians for Choice (Box-folder Box 71, Folder 14)
    - V.O.I.C.E.-The "Squeal Rule" (Box-folder Box 71, Folder 15)
  - Women's Issues
    - Commission on Status of Women (Proposal for Norfolk) (Box-folder Box 71, Folder 16)
    - Response to Tony Snow (Box-folder Box 71, Folder 17)
    - Washington Post Article February 24, 1980 (Box-folder Box 71, Folder 18)
    - Women of the House of Delegates 1924-1978 (Box-folder Box 71, Folder 19)
    - Equal Rights Amendment Forum at Old Dominion University October 17, 1981 (Box-folder Box 71, Folder 20)
    - Women and Politics-Political Issues Impacting on Career Women (Box-folder Box 71, Folder 21)
    - National Women's Political Caucus (NWPC) 1982-1984 (Box-folder Box 71, Folder 22)
    - National Women's Political Caucus (NWPC) 1985-1986 (Box-folder Box 71, Folder 23)
    - "Good Guys-Good Gals" (NWPC) 1987-1991 (Box-folder Box 71, Folder 24)
    - Women's Political Caucus-Marital Rape (Box-folder Box 71, Folder 25)
    - Women's Political Caucus-State and By-laws (Box-folder Box 71, Folder 26)
    - Testimony-Edythe Harrison Statement: J. Harvie Wilkinson III 1984 (Box-folder Box 71, Folder 27)
  - Old Dominion University-Women In Leadership
    - ODU Lecture Series (Box-folder Box 71, Folder 28)
    - Edythe Harrison Teaching at Old Dominion University (Box-folder Box 71, Folder 29)
    - Course and Program Description (Box-folder Box 71, Folder 30)
    - Lecture Notes (Box-folder Box 71, Folder 31)
    - Course Materials (Box-folder Box 71, Folder 32)
    - Reports, Pamphlets, and Brochures (Box-folder Box 72, Folder 1)
    - Women's Studies (Box-folder Box 72, Folder 2)
    - Friends of Women's Studies (Box-folder Box 72, Folder 3)
    - Finance-Friends of Women's Studies Member Roster (Box-folder Box 72, Folder 4)
    - Friends Material From Carolyn (University of Cincinnati Women's Studies) (Box-folder Box 72, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Letter Recommending Edythe Harrison for Norfolk City Council September 1968 (Box-folder Box 72, Folder 6)
    - Postcard, Edythe Harrison of Precinct Committeewoman (Box-folder Box 72, Folder 7)
    - Virginia Observer February 1982 (Box-folder Box 72, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence with Charles S. Robb (Box-folder Box 72, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous Invitations 1981-1982 (Box-folder Box 72, Folder 10)
    - Certificates 1981, 1984 (Box-folder Box 72, Folder 11)
    - Photographs (Box-folder Box 72, Folder 12)
    - Slides (all same portrait of Edythe Harrison) (Box-folder Box 72, Folder 13)
    - National Conference of Christians and Jews 1978-1979 (Box-folder Box 72, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder Box 72, Folder 15)
  - Reports & Publications
    - Women as Candidates in the 1984 congressional Elections: A Post-Election Survey of Five Congressional Districts, NWPC November 1984 (Box-folder Box 72, Folder 16)
    - Elected Women Organize: Statewide Associations, Center for the American Woman in Politics (CAWP) by Wendy S. Strimling (Box-folder Box 72, Folder 17)
    - Gettting Women Appointed: New Jersey's Bipartisan Coalition (CAWP) by Kathy A. Stanwick 1984 (Box-folder Box 72, Folder 18)
    - Political Women Tell What it Takes (CAWP) by Kathy A. Stanwick 1983 (Box-folder Box 72, Folder 19)
    - Women Make a Difference (CAWP) by Kathy A. Stanwick and Katherine E. Kleeman 1983 (Box-folder Box 72, Folder 20)
    - Women's PACs (CAWP) by Katherine E. Kleeman 1983 (Box-folder Box 72, Folder 21)
    - Women's Routes to Elective Office: A Comparison with Men's (CAWP), by Susan J. Carroll and Wendy S. Strimling 1983 (Box-folder Box 72, Folder 22)
    - Constitutional Inequality: The Political Fortunes of the Equal Rights Ammendment, Brookings Institution, by Gilbert Y. Steiner 1985 (Box-folder Box 73, Folder 1)
    - Options for Conducting a Pay Equity Study of Federal Pay and Classification Systems: Report by the Comptroller General of the United States March 1, 1985 (Box-folder Box 73, Folder 2)
    - Comments on report on Comparable Worth by the United States Commission on Civil Rights, GAO June 1985 (Box-folder Box 73, Folder 3)
    - Description of Selected Nonfederal Job Evaluation Systems, GAO July 1985 (Box-folder Box 73, Folder 4)
    - Description of Selected Systems for Classifying Federal Civilian Positions and Personnel, GAO July 1984 (Box-folder Box 73, Folder 5)
    - Distribution of Male and Female Employees in Four Federal Classification Systems, GAO November 1984 (Box-folder Box 73, Folder 6)
    - Comparable Worth: Issue for the 80's, A Consultaion of the U.S. Commission on Civil Rights, Vol. 1 June 6-7, 1984 (Box-folder Box 73, Folder 7)
    - Comparable Worth: Issue for the 80's, A Consultaion of the U.S. Commission on Civil Rights, Vol. 2 June 6-7, 1984 (Box-folder Box 73, Folder 8)
    - Comparable Worth: An Anaylsis and Recommendations, Report of the U.S. Commission on Civil Rights June 1985 (Box-folder Box 73, Folder 9)
    - Sex Discrimination and Title VII in Virginia: A Report of the Virginia Advisory Committee ot the U.S. Commission on Civil Rights April 1981 (Box-folder Box 73, Folder 10)
    - The 1985 Virginian Slims American Women's Opinion Poll, A Study Conducted by the Roper Organization 1985 (Box-folder Box 73, Folder 11)
    - Beyond the Myths: The Families Helped by the AFDC Program 2nd Edition, by Barbara Leyser, Adele M. Blong, and Juidth A. Riggs 1985 (Box-folder Box 73, Folder 12)
    - Tidewater Virginian, A Business Magazine of Southeastern Virginia January, August, September 1981 (Box-folder Box 74, Folder 1)
    - Renewing America's Promise: A Democratic Blueprint for Our Nation's Future, National House Democratic Caucus January 1984 (Box-folder Box 74, Folder 2)
    - Art and the States, National Conference of State Legislatures, compiled by Larry Briskin 1981 (Box-folder Box 74, Folder 3)
    - Virginia Legislative Handbooks 1980-1986 (Box-folder Box 74, Folder 4)
    - Progressive Rock Classics Songbook, Warner Bros. Publications (Box-folder Box 74, Folder 5)
    - National Air and Space Museum, Smithsonian Institution (Box-folder Box 74, Folder 6)
  - Oversized Materials
    - Cross Reference Directory Norfolk-Portsmouth, Chesapeake, and Virginia Beach October 1981 (Box Box 75)
    - Birthday Card and Newspaper Clipping from supporters in Clifton Forge, VA September 17, 1984 (Box Box 75)
    - Norfolk Compass August 15-16, 1979 (Box Box 75)
    - UJF News June 1, 1979 (Box Box 75)
    - Washington Jewish Week May 24, 1989 (Box Box 75)
    - Virginian Pilot/Ledger Star-Section A December 5, 1991 and November 25, 1969 (Box Box 75)
    - Portfolio October 20, 1987; June 21, 1988; November 22 1988; October 26, 1993 (Box Box 75)
    - New York Times August 9, 1974 and June 11, 1984 (Box Box 75)
    - Wall Street Journal, Section 2 June 5, 1984 (Box Box 75)
    - Tidal Times January 1982 (Box Box 75)
    - Women's American ORT Reporter May/June 1976 (Box Box 75)
    - National NOW Times July/August 1984 (Box Box 75)
    - Electoral Districts and Voting Precincts in the City of Norfolk, VA July 12, 1983 (Box Box 75)
    - Electoral Districts and Voting Precincts in the City of Chesapeake, VA March 1, 1980 (Box Box 75)
    - Sample Ballot, County of Fairfax November 6, 1984 (Box Box 75)
- Audio and Video Tapes
  - Audio Cassette Tapes
    - Edythe Harrison-"Vote for ME" and "The House Race" May 31, 1979 (Box Box 76)
    - "Edie on WTAR, Women's Political Caucus" February 25, 1983 (Box Box 76)
    - "Edie '84" Tape I (Box Box 76)
    - "Edie '84" Tape II (Box Box 76)
    - "Roanoke Office Opening" September 4, 1984 (Box Box 76)
    - "Birthday Party Tape" Recorded 11 pm September 14, 1984 (Box Box 76)
    - "Agenda, News Conference, Statehouse" & "Daily Press/Times Herald Q & A" October 3, 1984 (Box Box 76)
    - "Edie, The Talk Shows" October 23, 1984 (Box Box 76)
    - "Side 1-Deficit, Taxes" & "Side 2-Taxes (continued)" (Box Box 76)
    - "Side 3-9th District" & "Side 4-Strip Mining, N. Va Issues, Ed Grandes, Harris Miller" (Box Box 76)
    - "Side 5-N. VA Harris Miller" & Side 6-N. VA Harris Miller" (Box Box 76)
    - "Final News Conference, Concession Speech" (Box Box 76)
    - Unlabeled-Miscellaneous music (Box Box 76)
  - Reel to Reel Audio Tapes
    - "Norfolk's Five: #1 'Building' without Disclaimer: 60 Radio, # 2 'Symphony' without Disclaimer: 60 Radio," 7-1/2 IPS Mono Dub, Dan Advertising September 1, 1981 (Box box 76)
    - "Edie Harrison-Harrison Voice w/disclaimer", Mono 15 September 11, 1984 (Box Box 76)
    - "Edie Harrison-Hammer Away": 60, 15 IPS, Produced by Joe White Communications October 17, 1984 (Box Box 76)
    - "Edie Harrison for U.S. Senate-Hammer Away": 60, 7-1/2 IPS, Tails Out October 18, 1984 (Box Box 76)
    - "Edie Harrison for Senate, 60"-Wins for Virginia-Tails Out (no date) (Box Box 76)
  - Video Tapes
    - 2" TV Tape: Edie Harrison for U.S. Senate 1) "Common Sense"; 2) "Less Is Less-A," produced by Joe Slade White September 4, 1984
    - 2" TV Tape: Edie Harrison for Seanate Campaign, "Bye John" :30 TV, EHTV-3, produced by Joe Slade White September 6, 1984
    - 2" TV Tape: Joe Slade White, Edie Harrison for U.S. Senate, "Common Sense" October 29, 1984
    - Beta Video Tape: UVA vs. Indiana Final Four, Edie on TV news with family 1984
    - VHS Video Tape: "Edie Campaign '84"
    - VHS Video Tape: "Harrison Campaign, Norfolk Convention Speech"
    - MBU 18s Master Brodcast Videocassettes 3/4" tapes (untitled, undated)(four tapes)